DANILA RASSOKHIN

Yerevan, Armenia (ready to relocate)

danilarassokhin@gmail.com • Telegram: @RassokhinD • https://linkedin.com/in/danilarassokhin

SUMMARY

Java/Kotlin developer with three years of experience building and maintaining applications using Spring Boot, Hibernate, and related technologies. I have improved application performance and reduced errors, and I've helped make development processes more efficient. I share my knowledge through mentoring, technical interviews, writing about Java, Spring, and Postgres on Medium, and by creating a free Prolog programming course. I'm looking for a challenging Java Engineer role where I can use my skills to work on important projects.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

YLAB

Middle Java/Kotlin Developer

Aug 2023 - Present

- Optimized the image generation process, resulting in a 5x reduction in RAM usage, leading to improved application stability and reduced server costs
- Implemented image compression using ImageIO, preserving original resolution; This resulted in a 30% reduction of S3 bucket size and lower storage costs
- Replaced Jasper Reports with Apache POI for Excel report generation, resulting in a 10% increase in report generation speed
- Introduced Camunda BPMN scheme testing, reducing runtime bugs by 20%
- Developed Kotlin-based testing utilities with a user-friendly DSL for Camunda, increasing test writing speed by 15% and boosting team's velocity by 5%
- Achieved 100% test coverage for two large BPMN schemes, comprising over 700 elements and 1100 flows
- Enhanced team efficiency through a new practice, resulting in 2-3 additional closed business tasks per sprint
- Performed code reviews for over 100 interns in an internal Java course and more than 20 interviews

YLAB

Junior Java/Kotlin Developer

May 2023 - Aug 2023

- Covered 7 BPMN processes for Camunda with integration tests, resulting in improved stability
- Achieved test coverage of 97% for 15 Spring microservices using unit tests and integration tests

YLAB

Junior Java/Kotlin Developer

Ост 2022 - Мау 2023

- Designed and developed a BPMN migration tool, similar to Liquibase, that accelerated development by 10%
- Created a REST connector for Camunda 8 for distributed logging and reduced error investigation time by 10%
- Created a job worker for Camunda 8 to enable uploading and downloading files from S3 within BPMN tasks
- Redesigned the search functionality over Elasticsearch to support displaying over 10,000 documents

EDUCATION

KUBAN STATE UNIVERSITY

Krasnodar, Russia

2022-2024

Master of Informatics And Applied Mathematics

Studied computer science, including algorithms, Java, relational databases, mathematical analysis, and discrete mathematics. Participated in several conferences and authored papers on cryptography and bioinformatics.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming languages: Java, Kotlin
- Frameworks: Spring, Spring Boot, Hibernate, JOOQ, Camunda, gRPC
- Databases and platforms: Postgres, Apache Kafka, Elasticsearch, Redis
- Tools: Docker, CI/CD, Apache Avro
- System design: Microservices, REST API, Gateway, Reactive
- Languages: Russian (native), English (B2)